[Music]
Welcome to the busy central launch
edition for 2025 release wave 2. I will
try to present what is new in copilot
for sustainability together with my
colleague uh tensel. Before we go into
details, I would like to emphasize a few
business values. uh one of the most
important is that you can use you can
calculate emissions even if you do not
have all completed data. So even if you
do not have emission factors you can
calculate relatively easy. So you can
then update emission factors really
easy. You can keep uh information about
verify source. So it will be really easy
later for auditing. And then about
maintenance in the future all the all
these emission factors you can easily
again update and keep them updated and
accurate all the time. So you can be
focused on what is really important for
measuring and reporting sustainability
information and not to update all small
details especially about emission
factors. So how copilot uh works I will
briefly show you basic workflow.
First you need to have prepared some
user input. So you need to prepare your
sustainability journal and even as I
said even if you do not have emission
factors all good you need to have only
basic details about how many liters of
fuel you consume or how many kilometers
you passed where you travel just some
basic details without specific
information about emission factors and
then copilot will get the formula for
all of these specific situations
then formula will be breakdown
and in this moment LLM will try to find
emission factor based on your
information. How and where? First
uh LLM will try to find emission factor
in updated in uploaded file in a system.
I will show you how you can do it. And
then if there is no uploaded
information, if there is not something
you already uh prepared, system will go
outside and try to find a public
sources. Once we have collected emission
factors, everything will be
automatically calculated.
about how to prepare emission factors.
You will find new place uh for emission
uh factor sources. So what you need to
do find official information if this is
already an Excel good if not you need to
copy this information into the Excel
file then upload to this specific new
page emission source setup relatively
easy art will show where you can find it
and then this is not about one excel
file you can upload as many files as you
have what exactly so if your company is
working in two or three countries you
can prepare emission factors different
from country to country or you can do by
type. For example, you can have you can
have one emission factor file for your
country. What is the most common but if
you are working with one machine
producer, you can get specific file for
all these machines. So you can use
really accurate information for all your
machines you are handling in your
company. So you can combine different uh
types of files.
Um what is important
keep only information you really need
because if Excel file has thousands
thousands of lines probably it will be a
problem for calculating. So you are not
supposed just to copy any Excel file you
need to prepare it to use only what you
really need for your company and what is
important we prepare this this way so
you can keep this per specific period.
So if your emission factors are not
related for some specific periods, you
will just uh make uh empty fields
starting and ending date. So you are
good. But if you want for auditing to
update your emission factors every year
to have new, you can say okay for one
year then for next year you will prepare
new period and update new emission
factors. So the system will keep all
this information for auditing. Every
time when you use new emission factors
system can easily connect with the
information what you really used. So now
Arthur will show you how it looks in a
practice. Arthur,
thank you for introduction Alexander. U
so I'm going to start demoing the
feature from sustainability journal. I
have made all the necessary setup in
this environment. And here you can
notice the new action calculate CO2. Um
I'm going to click it and then we can
explore the results from Copilot.
So it's generating the results for all
for all lines and then uh what do we
have uh now here? So let's start from
top. We have one line auto suggested um
for the company car. Uh the reason is
that we already had a mission factor for
this line. So there was no reason to
send it to copilot. And then two out of
three lines uh have been sent to copilot
and we got actually the results. For the
first line uh we have uh the emission
factor taken from the source. You can
take a look on the column and the source
is taken from the file that I previously
uploaded. I will show this to you. Uh
and copilot was able to correctly
identify uh the category and take the
emission factor from this category. For
the second one, we have um information
from the uh from the uh uh public uh
because um the country for the second
line is Germany and not the UK. Uh the
file that I upload uh now what we can do
um we can drill down to copilot
suggested lines field and then we can
explore additional uh information here.
So instead of the total emission here
the final result that is uh required for
sustainability journal below we can see
the calculation explanation and this is
the way how you can verify that the
feature works fine. So it contains uh
the formula formula breakdown and all
the values. It starts with identifying
the distance uh and as you can see it
identifies the distance London to
framework and since this is the round
trip so it's multiplied by two uh and we
have the total distance. Now on the
second line we multiply the total
distance by emission factor and we have
uh the final total emission result uh
which uh aligns with what you see in the
emission CO2 here. And for the second
line uh the formula is different. It
easy one takes number of nights and then
multiplied emission factor. Perfect. So
we verified all the results. We see that
accurate. We close the page and then we
can click keep it. We want to take the
information from the from the suggestion
from the compilot uh to the journal. So
we click keep it. Uh and here I set it
up uh the way that I only want to save
emission factor for the second line. uh
I can click account subcategory and I
can click show details and I can see
that the mesh factor is saved uh for
this subcategory. So the next time I'm
going to use uh this subcategory uh it
will be automatically uh generated and
not sent to copilot. Um now
few words about the about the uploaded
file. As Alexander said, uh we are able
now to upload all those Excel files to
emission source setup. And here's how it
looks like. I uploaded file specifically
for UK and specifically for this years.
Uh I can create additional lines,
specify different dates. So in this
case, we keep auditing for all those
files. So you don't need to delete the
files. You can basically create the new
ones and then you can track all the
history going forward. And that
concludes my demo. Back to you,
Alexander. Thank you Arthur for this
great demo and what is the most
important now as we said you can be
focused on easily measuring all your
sustainability information. So even if
you do not have already prepared the
emission factors you can easily update
upload information with Excel with the
list emission factors and use copilot
for finding and locating all of them and
of course calculating. And before we
finish this session, I would like to
remind you to all important uh places
where you can find additional
information about Business Central. So
please remember these links. Then you
can subscribe on our LinkedIn weekly
news and all announcements will be
there. So this is important to track
what is done in a busy central side. And
when you watch this video, please go to
AKMMSBC
YouTube to find all other interesting
videos from this uh busy central launch
event and from previous ones.
Thank you for watching this session.